&gt；&gt；Kyle：动态范围怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Kyle: What about dynamic scope?
我说过它存在于一些语言中，它不存在于JavaScript中。
I said that it exists in some languages, it does not exist in JavaScript.
所以这完全是理论上的。
So this is entirely theoretical.
但如果JavaScript中确实存在，这就是动态代码的工作方式。
But if this did exist in JavaScript, this is how dynamics code would work.
您注意到第3行的函数ask正在引用
You noticed the function on line 3, the function ask, is making reference to
在自己的作用域中不存在的名为Teacher的变量。
a variable called teacher that does not exist in its own scope.
我们通常会认为它是对该变量的解析
And we would normally think of it as resolving to that variable
因为这就是我们从词汇上思考的方式。
because that's how we think lexically.
但是在动态限定作用域的语言中，它甚至不会查询词法作用域
But in a dynamically scoped language, it wouldn't even consult the lexical scope
筑巢时，它会说，嘿，问是从哪里来的。
nesting, it would say, hey, where was ask called from.
问是从哪里打来的？
So where was ask called from?
它是从其他类的作用域中调用的，并且
It was called from the scope of other class and
它将最终将教师解析为该变量。
it would end up resolving teacher to that variable.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：那么你能看到动态作用域的概念就是这个概念吗
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Can you see then that the idea of a dynamic scope is the idea
函数对其变量的引用取决于
that a function's references to its variables are depended upon where
那个函数是从哪里调用的？
that function was called from?
从100个不同的地方调用相同的函数最终得到100
The same function called from 100 different places ends up giving 100
对于变量是什么的不同答案，可能听起来像是混乱，但
different answers to what the variables are, that may sound like chaos but
你也应该认为这听起来像是惊人的灵活性和
you should also think of that as sounding like an amazing amount of flexibility and
重复使用。
reuse.
想象一下编写一个可以在所有这些不同的函数中重用的函数
Imagine writing one function that could be re-used in all of those different
顺便说一句，这些都不是对或错的。
contexts, and these are not right or wrong, by the way.
它并不像动态范围是坏的和邪恶的或奇怪的，它只是如此
It's not like dynamic scope is bad and evil or weird, it's just so
我们不熟悉，因为我们不是那样想的。
unfamiliar to us because we don't think of it that way.
但是如果你只写过动态作用域并且有人解释过
But if you had only ever written dynamic scope and somebody explained
他们会说，词法范围，但是你喜欢重用你的函数吗？
lexical scope, they'd say, but how do you like re-use your functions?
[笑]对吧？
[LAUGH] Right?
他们会有和我们发自内心的一样的反应
They'd have the same reaction that we might viscerally have to this
代码片断。
code snippet.
因此，我们应该从动态作用域中得到的是，它是确定的作用域
So what we should get from dynamic scope is that it is scope that is determined
基于运行时的条件，
based upon the conditions at runtime,
而词汇范围是在作者时确定的。
whereas lexical scope is determined at author time.
即使JavaScript没有动态范围，
Even though JavaScript does not have dynamic scope,
JavaScript确实有一种机制为我们提供了同样的灵活性，
JavaScript does have a mechanism that gives us this same kind of flexibility,
我们稍后会在课程中谈到这一点。
and we'll talk about that later in our course.
所以我希望你现在把这个区别记在脑海里，
So I want you to keep in your mind right now this difference between fixed,
可预测的，动态的，灵活的。
predictable, and dynamic, and flexible.